The one is not the only.
Thor: Love and Thunder is a fantasy, action,
comedy film directed by Taika Waititi.
After his retirement is interrupted by Gorr the God Butcher, a galactic killer who seeks the extinction of the gods, Thor Odinson
enlists the help of King Valkyrie, Korg, and ex-girlfriend Jane Foster, who now wields Mjolnir as the Mighty Thor.
Together they embark upon a harrowing cosmic adventure to uncover the mystery of
the God Butcher’s vengeance and stop him before it’s too late.
Thor, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Jane Foster / The Mighty Thor, played by Natalie Portman.
Gorr, played by Christian Bale.
King Valkyrie, played by Tessa Thompson.
Korg / Old Kronan God (voice), played by Taika Waititi.
Zeus, played by Russell Crowe.
Thor: Love and Thunder is a 2022 American superhero film based
on Marvel Comics featuring the character Thor.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the sequel
to Thor: Ragnarok (2017) and the 29th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Taika Waititi, who co-wrote the screenplay with Jennifer Kaytin Robinson, and stars Chris Hemsworth as
Thor alongside Christian Bale, Tessa Thompson, Jaimie Alexander, Waititi, Russell Crowe, and Natalie Portman.
In the film, Thor tries to find inner peace, but must return to action and recruit Valkyrie (Thompson), Korg (Waititi), and
Jane Foster (Portman)—who is now the Mighty Thor—to stop Gorr the God Butcher (Bale) from eliminating all gods.
Hemsworth and Waititi had discussed plans for a
sequel to Ragnarok by January 2018.
Love and Thunder was announced in July 2019, with Hemsworth, Waititi, and Thompson
all set to return, as well as Portman who did not appear in Ragnarok.
Waititi wanted to differentiate Love and Thunder from Ragnarok, seeking
to make a romance film and 1980s-inspired adventure.
He adapted elements from Jason Aaron's run on Thor comic books during the 2010s, which similarly debuted
Gorr and saw Foster take on the mantle and powers of Thor whilst under treatment for cancer.
Robinson joined to contribute to the script in February 2020, and further casting was
revealed later that year including the appearance of the Guardians of the Galaxy.
Production was expected to begin in late 2020 but
was delayed by the COVID-19 pandemic.
Filming ultimately began in January 2021 in Sydney, Australia with Barry Idoine as
the director of photography, and concluded at the beginning of June.
Thor: Love and Thunder premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on June 23,
2022, and was released in the United States on July 8, as part of Phase Four of the MCU.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the performances of Hemsworth,
Bale and Portman, but criticized its visual effects and tonal inconsistencies.
The film grossed $760.9 million worldwide, making it the eighth-highest-grossing film of
2022, as well as the second-highest-grossing film in the Thor franchise.
The film explores themes of hero, ex-girlfriend,
superhero, greek mythology, based on comic.
The tone is lighthearted.